{
	"year": 2012,
	"department": "ece",
	"questions": [{
            "question_number": 1,
			"question": "The current i through the base of a silicon npn transistor is os t m . At 300 K, the r in the small signal model of the transistor is ",
			"answer1":"25 Ω",
			"answer2":"27 5 Ω",
			"answer3":"25 Ω",
			"answer4":"22 5 Ω",
			"correct": "25 Ω"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 2,
	       "question": "The power spectral density of a real process X(t) for positive frequencies is shown below The values of t and t,respectively,are ",
			"answer1":"6 /π,0",
			"answer2":"64 /π,0",
			"answer3":"64 /π, 2 /(π√2)",
			"answer4":"6 /π, 2 /(π√2)",
			"correct": "64 /π,0"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 3,
	"question": "In a baseband communications link, frequencies upto 3500 Hz are used for signaling. Using a raised cosine pulse with 75% excess bandwidth and for no inter-symbol interference, the maximum possible signaling rate in symbols per second is  ",
			"answer1":"1750",
			"answer2":"2625",
			"answer3":"4000", 
			"answer4":"5250",
			"correct": "4000"
         },
         {
             "question_number": 4,
        "question": "A plane wave propagating in air with E= (8 ̂ 6 ̂ 5 ̂ )e V/ m is incident on perfectly conducting slab positioned at x<=0. The E field of the reflected wave is",
            "answer1":"(-8a^x+6a^y- 5a^z)e^j(wt-3x-4y)V/m",
			"answer2":"(-8a^x-6a^y- 5a^z)e^j(wt+3x+4y)V/m",
			"answer3":"(-8a^x+6a^y- 5a^z)e^j(wt+3x+4y)V/m", 
			"answer4":"(-8a^x-6a^y- 5a^z)e^j(wt-3x-4y)V/m",
			"correct": "(-8a^x-6a^y- 5a^z)e^j(wt-3x-4y)V/m"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 5,
			"question": "The electric field of a uniform plane electromagnetic wave in free space, along the positive x direction, is given by  E= 10    ( ̂ay+j ̂az )e^-j25x The frequency and polarization of the wave, respectively,- are ",
            "answer1":"1.2 GHz and left circular",
			"answer2":"4 Hz and left circular",
			"answer3":"1.2 GHz and right circular", 
			"answer4":"4 Hz and right circular",
			"correct": "1.2 GHz and left circular"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 6,
			"question": "Consider the given circuit In this circuit, the race around ",
            "answer1":"Does not occur",
			"answer2":"Occurs when CLK = 0",
			"answer3":"Occurs when CLK = 1 and A =B =1", 
			"answer4":"Occurs when clk = 1 and A = B = 0",
			"correct": "Does not occur"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 7,
			"question": "The output Y of a 2-bit comparator is logic 1 whenever the 2-bit input A is greater than the 2bit input B. The number of combinations for which the output is logic 1, is ",
            "answer1":"4",
			"answer2":"6",
			"answer3":"8", 
			"answer4":"10",
			"correct": "6"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 8,
			"question": "The I-V characteristics of the diode in the circuit given below are i={(v-0.7/500)A,v>=0.7V and 0A, v<=V The current in the circuit is ",
            "answer1":"10 mA",
			"answer2":"9.3 mA",
			"answer3":"6.67 mA", 
			"answer4":"6.2 mA",
			"correct": "6.2 mA"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 9,
			"question": "In the following figure, C1 and C2 are ideal capacitors. C1 has been charged to 12 V before the ideal switch S is closed at t = 0. The current i(t) for all t is.",
            "answer1":"Zero",
			"answer2":"a step function",
			"answer3":"an exponentially decaying function", 
			"answer4":"an impulse function",
			"correct": "an impulse function"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 10,
			"question": "The average power delivered to an impedance (4-j3)ohm by a current  5cos (100 t+100) A is",
            "answer1":"44.2 W",
			"answer2":"50 W",
			"answer3":"62.5 W", 
			"answer4":"125 W",
			"correct": "50 W"
		},
        {
            "question_number": 11,
			"question": "With initial condition x(1) = 0.5, the solution of the differential equation, t dx/dt + x = t is ",
            "answer1":"x = t-1/2",
			"answer2":"x = t^2-1/2",
			"answer3":"xt = t^2/2", 
			"answer4":"x = t/2",
			"correct": "xt = t^2/2"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 12,
			"question": "The diodes and capacitors in the circuit shown are ideal. The voltage v(t) across the diode is",
            "answer1":"cos(ωt) – 1",
			"answer2":"sin(ωt)",
			"answer3":"1-cos(ωt)", 
			"answer4":"1-sin(ωt)",
			"correct": "cos(ωt) – 1"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 13,
			"question": "In the circuit shown ",
            "answer1":"Y=AB + C",
			"answer2":"Y=(A+B)C",
			"answer3":"Y=(A+B) + C", 
			"answer4":"Y=AB + C",
			"correct": "Y=AB + C"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 14,
			"question": "A source alphabet consists of N symbols with the probability of the first two symbols being the same. A source encoder increases the probability of the first symbol by a small amount ε and decreases that of a 2nd by ε AftEr encoding, the entropy of the source",
            "answer1":"Increases",
			"answer2":"Remains the same",
			"answer3":"Increases only if N = 2", 
			"answer4":"Decreases",
			"correct": "Decreases"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 15,
			"question": "A coaxial cable with an inner diameter of 1 mm and outer diameter of 2.4 mm is filled with a dielectric   of relative   permittivity   10.89.  Given u=4π*10^-7H/m, ε0=10^-9/36π F/m the characteristic impedance of the cable is ",
            "answer1":"330 Ω",
			"answer2":"100 Ω",
			"answer3":"143.3 Ω", 
			"answer4":"43.4 Ω",
			"correct": "43.4 Ω"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 16,
			"question": "The radiation pattern of an antenna in spherical co-ordinates is given by   F(θ)=cos4θ; 0<=θ<=π/2 The directivity of the antenna is ",
            "answer1":"10dB",
			"answer2":"12.6dB",
			"answer3":"11.5dB", 
			"answer4":"18dB",
			"correct": "10dB"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 17,
			"question": "If x[n]=(1/3)|n|-(1/2)^n u[n], then the region of convergence (ROC) of its Z-transform in the Z-plane will be ",
             "answer1":"1/3<|Z|<3",
			"answer2":"1/3<|Z|<1/2",
			"answer3":"1/2<|Z|<3", 
			"answer4":"1/3<|Z|",
			"correct": "1/2<|Z|<3"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 18,
			"question": "A system with transfer function G(s)=(s^2+9)(s+2)/(s+1)(s+3)(s+4) is is excited   bysin(ωt) . The steady-state output of the system is zero at  ",
            "answer1":"ω= 1 rad/s",
			"answer2":"ω= 2 rad/s",
			"answer3":"ω= 3 rad/s", 
			"answer4":"ω= 4 rad/s",
			"correct": "ω= 1 rad/s"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 19,
			"question": "The impedance looking into nodes 1 and 2 in the given circuit is ",
             "answer1":"50 Ω",
			"answer2":"100 Ω",
			"answer3":"5 Ω", 
			"answer4":"10.1 Ω",
			"correct": "50 Ω"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 20,
			"question": "In the circuit shown below, the current through the inductor is ",
            "answer1":"(2/1+j)A",
			"answer2":"(1/1+j)A",
			"answer3":"(-1/1+j)A", 
			"answer4":"0A",
			"correct": "(-1/1+j)A"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 21,
			"question": "Given f (z)=(1/z+1)-(2/z+3). If C is a counterclockwise path in the z – plane such that |z+1| =1, the value of (1/2πj)∮ f(z) dz is ",
            "answer1":"-2",
			"answer2":"-1",
			"answer3":"1", 
			"answer4":"2",
			"correct": "1"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 22,
			"question": "Two independent random variables X and Y are uniformly distributed in the interval [-1,1]. The probability that max [X,Y] is less than 1/2 is ",
            "answer1":"3/4",
			"answer2":"9/16",
			"answer3":"1/4", 
			"answer4":"2/3",
			"correct": "9/16"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 23,
			"question": "If x = √-1 , then the value of x^x  is ",
            "answer1":"e^-π/2",
			"answer2":"e^π/2",
			"answer3":"x", 
			"answer4":"1",
			"correct": "e^-π/2"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 24,
			"question": "The source of a silicon (ni = 1010per cm3) n-channel MOS transistor has an area of 1 sqm and a depth of 1 m.If the dopant density in the source is 10^19/cm3 , the number of holes in the source region with the above volume is approximately",
            "answer1":"10^7",
			"answer2":"100",
			"answer3":"10", 
			"answer4":"0",
			"correct": "0"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 25,
			"question": "A BPSK scheme operating over an AWGN channel with noise power spectral density of N0/2, uses equiprobable signals s1(t)= √2E/T sin(ωt) and  s2(t)= -√2E/T sin(ωt) over the symbol interval, (0, T). If the local oscillator in a coherent receiver is ahead in phase by 45 degree with respect to the received signal, the probability of error in the resulting system is",
            "answer1":"Q(√2E/N)",
			"answer2":"Q(√E/N)",
			"answer3":"Q(√E/2N)", 
			"answer4":"Q(√E/4N)",
			"correct": "Q(√E/N)"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 26,
			"question": "A transmission line with a characteristic impedance of 100 Ω is used to match a 50 Ω section to a 200 Ω section. If the matching is to be done both at 429 MHz and 1 GHz, the length of the transmission line can be approximately",
            "answer1":"82.5 cm",
			"answer2":"1.58m",
			"answer3":"1.85m", 
			"answer4":"1.75 m",
			"correct": "1.58m"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 27,
			"question": "The input x(t) and output y(t) of a system are related as y(t) = ∫ x(π)cos(3π)dπ. The system is ",
            "answer1":"time-invariant and stable",
			"answer2":"stable and not time-invariant",
			"answer3":"time-invariant and not stable", 
			"answer4":"not time-invariant and not stable",
			"correct": "not time-invariant and not stable"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 28,
			"question": "The Fourier transform of a signal h(t) is H(jω)=(2 cosω) (sin 2 ω)/ω. The value of h(0) is ",
            "answer1":"1/4",
			"answer2":"1/2",
			"answer3":"1", 
			"answer4":"2",
			"correct": "1"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 29,
			"question": "The direction of vector A is radially outward from the origin, with |A|=Kr^n  where r^2=x^2+y^2+z^2 and K is constant. The value of n for which V.A = 0 is ",
            "answer1":"-2",
			"answer2":"2",
			"answer3":"1", 
			"answer4":"0",
			"correct": "-2"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 30,
			"question": "A fair coin is tossed till a head appears for the first time probability that the number of required tosses  is odd , is ",
            "answer1":"1/3",
			"answer2":"1/2",
			"answer3":"2/3", 
			"answer4":"3/4",
			"correct": "2/3"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 31,
			"question": "A binary symmetric channel (BSC) has a transition probability of 1/8.  If the binary transmit symbol X is such that P(X = 0) = 9/10, then the probability of error for an optimum receiver will be ",
            "answer1":"7/80",
			"answer2":"63/80",
			"answer3":"9/10", 
			"answer4":"1/10",
			"correct": "1/10"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 32,
			"question": "Let y[n] denote the convolution of h[n] and g[n], where h[n]= (1/2)n u[n] and g[n] is causal sequence. If y[0]=1 and y[1]=1/2, then g[1] equals ",
            "answer1":"0",
			"answer2":"1/2",
			"answer3":"1", 
			"answer4":"3/2",
			"correct": "0"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 33,
			"question": "The maximum value of  f(x) =x^3-9x^2+24x+5 in the interval [1,6] is ",
            "answer1":"21",
			"answer2":"25",
			"answer3":"41", 
			"answer4":"46",
			"correct": "41"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 34,
			"question": "Given that A = [ -5 -3, 2 0] and I = [1 0, 0 1] , the value of A3 is ",
            "answer1":"15A+12I",
			"answer2":"19A + 30",
			"answer3":"17A + 15I", 
			"answer4":"17A + 21",
			"correct": "19A + 30"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 35,
			"question": "With 10 V dc connected at port A, the current drawn by 7Ω  connected at port B is ",
            "answer1":"3/7 A",
			"answer2":"5/7 A",
			"answer3":"1 A", 
			"answer4":"9/7 A",
			"correct": "1 A"
		},
        
        {
			"question_number": 36,
			"question": "For the same network, with 6 V dc connected at port A, 1Ω connected at port B draws 7/3 A. If 8 V dc is connected to port A, the open circuit voltage at port B is ",
            "answer1":"6 V",
			"answer2":"7 V",
			"answer3":"8 V", 
			"answer4":"9 V",
			"correct": "7 V"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 37,
			"question": "The gate-source overlap capacitance is approximately ",
            "answer1":"0.7 fF",
			"answer2":"0.7 pF",
			"answer3":"0.35 fF", 
			"answer4":"0.24 pF",
			"correct": "0.7 fF"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 38,
			"question": "The source-body junction capacitance is approximately ",
            "answer1":"2 fF",
			"answer2":"7 fF",
			"answer3":"2 pF", 
			"answer4":"7 pF",
			"correct": "2 fF"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 39,
			"question": "The magnetic field at a distance r from the center of the wire is proportional to ",
            "answer1":"r for r < a and 1/r2 for r > a",
			"answer2":"0 for r < a and 1/r  for r > a ",
			"answer3":"r for r < a and 1/r for r > a", 
			"answer4":"0 for r < a and 1/r2 for r > a",
			"correct": "r for r < a and 1/r for r > a"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 40,
			"question": "A hole of radius b (b < a) is now drilled along the length of the wire at a distance d from the center of the wire as shown below. The magnetic field inside the hole is ",
            "answer1":"uniform and depends only on d",
			"answer2":"uniform and depends only on b",
			"answer3":"uniform and depends on both b and d", 
			"answer4":"non uniform",
			"correct": "uniform and depends on both b and d"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 41,
			"question": "   Gc(s) is a lead compensator if ",
            "answer1":"A = 1,b = 2",
			"answer2":"A = -3,b = -1",
			"answer3":"A = 3,b = 2", 
			"answer4":"A = 3,b = 1",
			"correct": "A = 1,b = 2"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 42,
			"question": "The phase of the above lead compensator is maximum at ",
            "answer1":"√2 rad/s",
			"answer2":"√3 rad/s",
			"answer3":"√6 rad/s", 
			"answer4":"1/√3 rad/s",
			"correct": "√2 rad/s"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 43,
			"question": "One of the parts (A, B, C, D) in the sentence given below contains an ERROR. Which one of the following is INCORRECT? I requested that he should be given the driving test today instead of tomorrow",
            "answer1":"Requested that",
			"answer2":"Should be given",
			"answer3":"√The driving test", 
			"answer4":"Instead of-tomorrow",
			"correct": "Should be given"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 44,
			"question": "If (1.001)^1259=3.52 and (1.001)^2062 = 7.85, then (1.001)^3321=",
			"options": ["2.23", "4.33", "11.37", "27.64"],
			"correct_answer": "27.64",
			"correct_option_number": 4
            "answer1":"√2 rad/s",
			"answer2":"√3 rad/s",
			"answer3":"√6 rad/s", 
			"answer4":"1/√3 rad/s",
			"correct": "√2 rad/s"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 45,
			"question": "Choose the most appropriate alternative from the options given below to complete the following sentence: If the tired soldier wanted to lie down, he _________ the mattress out on the balcony. ",
            "answer1":"Should take",
			"answer2":"Shall take",
			"answer3":"Should have taken", 
			"answer4":"Will have taken",
			"correct": "Should take"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 46,
			"question": "Choose the most appropriate word from the options given below to complete the following sentence: Given the seriousness of the situation that he had to face, his _____ was impressive. ",
            "answer1":"beggary",
			"answer2":"nomenclature",
			"answer3":"jealous", 
			"answer4":"nonchalance",
			"correct": "nonchalance"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 47,
			"question": "Which one of the following options is the closest in meaning to the word given below? Latitude ",
            "answer1":"Eligibility",
			"answer2":"Freedom",
			"answer3":"Coercion", 
			"answer4":"Meticulousness",
			"correct": "Freedom"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 48,
			"question": "A and B are friends. They decide to meet between 1 PM and 2 PM on a given day. There is a condition that whoever arrives first will not wait for the other for more than 15 minutes. The probability that they will meet on that day is",
            "answer1":"1/4",
			"answer2":"1/16",
			"answer3":"7/16", 
			"answer4":"9/16",
			"correct": "1/4"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 49,
			"question": "One of the legacies of the Roman legions was discipline. In the legions, military law prevailed and discipline was brutal. Discipline on the battlefield kept units obedient, intact and fighting even when the odds and conditions were against them. Which one of the following statements best sums up the meaning of the above passage?",
            "answer1":"Thorough regimentation was the main reason for the efficiency of the Roman legions even in adverse circumstances",
			"answer2":"The legions were treated inhumanly as if the men were animals",
			"answer3":"Discipline was the armies' inheritance from their seniors ", 
			"answer4":" The harsh discipline to which the legions were subjected to led to the odds and conditions being…… against them",
			"correct": "Thorough regimentation was the main reason for the efficiency of the Roman legions even in adverse circumstances"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 50,
			"question": "Raju has 14 currency notes in his pocket consisting of only ₹ 20 notes and ₹ 10 notes. The total money value of the notes is ₹ 230. The number of ₹ 10 notes that Raju has is",
            "answer1":"5",
			"answer2":"6",
			"answer3":"9", 
			"answer4":"10",
			"correct": "5"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 51,
			"question": "There are eight bags of rice looking alike, seven of which have equal weight and one is slightly heavier. The weighing balance is of unlimited capacity. Using this balance, the minimum number of weighing’s required to identify the heavier bag is",
            "answer1":"2",
			"answer2":"3",
			"answer3":"4", 
			"answer4":"8",
			"correct": "2"
		},
        {
			"question_number": 52,
			"question": "The data given in the following table summarizes the monthly budget of an average household. Category= Food, Clothing, Rent, Savings, Other expenses. Amount (₹)  4000 1200 2000 1500 1800. The approximate percentage of the monthly budget NOT spent on savings is ",
            "answer1":"10%",
			"answer2":"14%",
			"answer3":"81%", 
			"answer4":"86%",
			"correct": "86%"
		}
	]
}